Travers La Ville

Address: 7201 Wood Hollow dr Austin, Tx 78731

Website: <u>lavillesolutions.com</u>
Email: <u>info@lavillesolutions.com</u>
Phone: (832) 917- 8602

MISSION STATEMENT

Self-motivated, expert level problem solver with more than eight years of working experience exploring new opportunities within the greater IT ecosystem. Although most of my experience is within technical project management, e-commerce content management and analytical reporting, I've recently bolstered my technical skills by completing multiple courses in HTML/CSS, Javascript, Version Control (Git/Github) and UI/UX.

As an added bonus, I'm a quick-study with most modern web technologies/frameworks and equally comfortable speaking with business-folk, tech-folk and end customers alike.

SKILLS

Technologies: html5, css3, javascript, mysql, lamp stack (php, server configuration, dns), version control / code

deployment (git), codeigniter

Software: linux, microsoft windows, filezilla, virtual box, microsoft office suite, adobe photoshop, video

editing, XAMPP

Platforms: magento, peoplesoft, drupal, wordpress, hostgator, digitalocean, spacecrafted, ad builder,

google analytics, cPanel, phpMyAdmin

Administrative and

Reporting:

content management, project / account management, qa / uat, analytical reports, technical writing, contracts, technical requirements documents, vision and spec documents, test plans,

web forms, web reports, ad-hoc reports, executive summaries

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

La Ville Solutions 2017 - Present

- Provided various technical services for multiple local businesses
- Project scoping and creation of statements of work
- Implementation and customization of Content Management Systems (Wordpress, Spacecrafted, Magento)
- Contributions to custom PHP application (Coffee App)

Brandmuscle, Inc.- Multiple Positions

2014 - 2017

Project Lead/Project Manager, Marketing Reporting Suite

- Managed multiple technical marketing projects for many Enterprise Customers (BMW, Sprint, Farmers)
- Formulated comprehensive test plans to be used during software migration
- Daily creation and management of dynamic web content (marketing, e-commerce) within various CMS's
- Ongoing QA and UAT for multiple customer websites, worked closely with design and development teams to resolve discrepancies

Authored, edited and published ongoing training videos/webinars

Business Analyst, Account Reconciliation

- Developed over 50 complex analytical queries in SQL to create graphic dashboards
- Regularly surfaced and resolved payment discrepancies and transactional disputes from custom in-house reporting suite
- Identified and remedied inefficiencies in company-wide invoicing process
- Lead weekly meetings with global team to address and resolve ongoing issues

-Promoted to Project Lead/Project Manager

Client Service Representative / Account Manager

- Maintaining client/business-to-business relationships
- Responsible for resolving financial data discrepancies above \$1 million threshold for ongoing projects
- Responsible for quarterly project scheduling and budget establishment
- Coordinated staffing needs for project support while adhering to project launch schedules
 - Promoted to Business Analyst Account Reconciliation

Just Brakes - Management / Service Writer

2013 - 2014

- Streamlined and digitized a hand-written process for quoting automotive service
- Worked daily with enterprise b2b software to manage orders and returns
- Identified and remedied discrepancies with billing and returns
- Authored and published corporate SOP regarding legal liability for services provided
- Actively maintained customer appointment schedules to ensure a timely customer experience
- Coordinated inter-office communication regarding sales campaigns and promotional offers

Connectivity Source - Multiple Positions

2009 - 2013

Service Technician Manager

- Dramatically increased franchise sales performance and overall store ranking
- Daily process of insurance claims and new orders via enterprise order management system
- Collaborated with insurance companies to process approximately 1,000 device claims per month
- Created training procedures to on-board more than 20 additional employees
- Miscellaneous managerial duties for service technician staff

Service Technician

- Resolved a multitude of issues with customer devices
- Received Sprint Service Technician certification
 - Promoted to Service Technician Manager

EDUCATION

Concordia University, Austin, TX

Present

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science